--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
协调: 影子
翻译: 轩一一 优兰达子 。私 风露清愁
校对: 有个饭团
会不会 很久以前 天空中曾经谧无繁星?
What if, once upon a time, there were no stars in the sky at all?
有没有可能 星星根本不是我们所想象的那样?
What if the stars are not what we think?
如果 满天繁星遥遥发出的光芒并不是来自于远空的恒星本身...
What if the light from afar doesn't come from the rays of distant suns...
而是来自于我们死后进入天堂时展开的羽翼?
but from our wings as we turn into angels?
2014年 纽约
命运召唤着芸芸众生
Destiny calls to each of us.
而在这个世界背后 还有另外一个世界 将我们紧紧相连
And there is a world behind the world where we are all connected.
成为伟大而更迭的计划中不可或缺的一环
All part of a great and moving plan.
奇迹无处不在
Magic is everywhere around us.
你只需要一双善于发现的眼睛
You just have to look.
去观察
Look.
仔细地观察
Look closely.
因为即使是时间和距离 也很可能暗藏玄机
For even time and distance are not what they appear to be.
1895年 纽约
下一位
Next.
先生 到你了
Sir, you're next.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你们必须原路返回
You'll have to go back.
什么?
What?
不 为什么? 我们...
No. No. Why? We...
你有肺病
It's pulmonary.
那... 孩子呢? 能让他过去吗?
Ah... What about the baby? Is there place for him?
如果我们只能原路返回的话 我们想留下他
If we have to go back, we leave him.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不是 你根本没听懂我的意思
No. You do not understand.
我们彼此相连
We are all connected.
每一个孩子在出生时就蕴含了造物的奇迹
Each baby born carries a miracle inside.
一个独特的目的
A unique purpose.
而这个奇迹对于每个人都是独一无二的
And that miracle is promised to one person and one person alone.
我们都是航海家 朝着命运的方向扬帆起航...
We are voyagers, set on a course towards destiny...
去找到命中注定的那个人
to find the one person our miracle is meant for.
但是请当心 当我们试图寻找光明...
But be warned, as we seek out the light...
黑暗也正凝聚如墨
darkness gathers.
而上帝与魔鬼之间永无止境地较量并非取决于兵力强弱...
And the eternal contest between God and Evil is not fought with great armies...
而是取决于每一份人生的选择
but one life at a time.
冬日奇缘
1916年 纽约
站住!
Stop right there!
彼得 滚回来!
Get back here, Pete!
- 快点回来!  - 呃!
- Get back here!  - Unh!
彼得 我也只是奉命行事而已啊!
Pete, them was just orders!
不用 别这样
No. Not like that.
咱们已经抓到他了
We have him now.
让我们慢慢来...
Let's do it slowly...
用刀子来结果他
with the knives.
抓住他!
Get him!
马儿 乖马儿
Horse. Horse.
马兄
Horse.
跑啊 快跑!
Go, go, go!
哥们儿快跑啊!
Go on. boy!
哇哦!
Whoa. Whoa, whoa! Whoa.
马兄! 拜托了! 不是这条路!
Horse! Come on! Other way!
错了!
Other way!
马兄!
Horse!
你是何方神圣?
What are you?
他弄到了那匹奇葩的马
He's got the goddamn horse.
下午好
Good afternoon.
管家说我应该穿着大衣
The butler told me I should leave my coat on.
唔
Mm.
我们屋里有人正在发烧
We have fever in the house.
潘先生 要配眼镜的是您妻子吗?
Is it your wife that needs spectacles, Mr. Penn?
她死了
Dead.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
都过去八年了
It's eight years ago.
有些人是你始终无法忘怀的
Still, you never stop missing them.
这眼镜是给我女儿配的
It's for my daughter.
她等会儿就下来
She'll be finished soon.
挺好听的 对吧? 勃拉姆斯的曲子
It is nice, isn't it? Brahms.
贝芙丽...
Beverly...
这位先生是来给你配眼镜的
this man has come to make you some new glasses.
别怕 不传染
Don't worry, it's not contagious.
不 不是
No, no.
我妹妹...
My sister...
她也得过这个
she had it.
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
这样比较好...
Better this way...
还是这样?
or this way?
她多大年纪?
How old was she?
你妹妹?
Your sister?
二十...
Twenty...
在她去世的时候
when she died.
你一定从未有过命不久矣的感觉
You never think you're as old as you're ever going to get.
没有
No.
我没有过这种感觉
I suppose not.
这样...
This way...
还是这样?
or this?
前一种
First.
发烧 可以让世界看起来美好得多
The fever, it can make things wonderful.
即使现在...
Even now...
我都能感觉到冬天就在我身边 他使屋里的光线变幻万千...
I can see winter as it turns around the room on the light...
如白色长矛般投射进来的光...
darting from white lances...
分散成一道道细细的光线...
to rays...
洒在银色的十字架上...
to silver crosses...
洒在镜片上...
to the optical glass...
洒在壁橱的火焰中 洒在光可鉴人的玻璃上
to the flames, to the reflective windows.
然后照亮我们每一个人
And illuminating each of us.
我病得越严重...
The sicker I become...
我就越能清醒地意识到这世间万事万物是由光紧密地联系
the more clearly I can see that everything is connected by light.
你有看这个的眼镜吗?
Do you have glasses for that?
嘿 塞西尔
Hey, Cecil.
额滴神啊
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
他不一般 是吧?
Yeah, he's something, isn't he?
而且 哥们儿 他会跳
And, boy, can he jump.
给我弄个马鞍 再来点儿燕麦...
I want a saddle, oats...
还有 给它弄张好点儿的毯子 开司米羊绒的
and I want a nice blanket for him. Cashmere.
这是你最值钱的赃物啊 彼得
He's the best duff you ever stole, Pete.
得了吧 他可不是赃物 塞西尔
Oh, he ain't duff, Cecil.
他是我的新朋友
He's me new partner.
对吧 马兄?
Aren't you, horse?
- 你在阁楼里躲不了多久的  - 为啥?
- You can't keep hiding out up in the attic.  - Why?
听说帕里把赏金提高三倍 让他的人到处找你
Word went out, Pearly's tripled the reward. He's got his guys looking everywhere.
混蛋 他今儿早上就找到我了
Ugly son of a bitch. He found me this morning.
还好马兄救了我一命
Horse saved my life.
我觉得我得出去躲躲 等夏天再回来 和我的马兄一起
I think I'll get out of town till summer, you know? Me and horse.
先偷到足够的东西够我俩过日子 然后等风头过去了再说 明白?
Steal enough to get us by. Just let this whole thing blow over, you know?
我觉得帕里不是那种会息事宁人的人
I don't see Pearly much as the blowing-over kind.
是啊
Yeah.
- 那是因为你担心的太多了 塞西尔  - 唔
- That's because you worry too much, Cecil.  - Heh.
帮我看一晚上马 成么?
Just board him for me, will you?
谢啦
Thanks.
彼得!
Pete!
你忘了拿...
You forgot your...
零钱
change.
我还在想你什么时候才会过来
I was wondering when you'd get here.
请注意
May I have your attention please.
第43列火车...
Train number 43...
正在4号站台检票上车
is now boarding on Track Number 4.
进来!
Enter!
为了主日的弥撒 圣派翠克大教堂准备举办篝火晚会
The fire at St. Paddy's is set for Sunday Mass.
那与我无关
That's not what matters to me.
但是他们承诺给我们每人500块买他的人头
But they reward everyone 500 for his head.
- 马呢?  - 一个价 对于一匹马而言这个价钱可不便宜
- And the horse?  - The same. Seems like a lot for a horse.
因为那不是一匹马
Well, that's because it's not a horse.
- 那是只狗  - 你刚说它是...
- It's a dog.  - You just said it was a...
至少就我们目前掌握的情况来看 他还没出城
As far as we can tell, he hasn't left the city.
那帮小子在密切监视着各处桥梁 纽约没那么大 他跑不了
Woola boys are watching all the bridges. New York's not that big. We'll find him.
- 你最好抓得住他  - 我保证 老板
- You better.  - I know, boss.
城里的气氛紧张压抑
People are scared and unhappy all over the city.
奇迹只完成了一半 如果算上布鲁克林 那就是一半多一点
Miracles are down by half. More if you count Brooklyn.
能说说彼得有什么特别之处吗?
If you don't mind me ask what's so special about Pete?
你以前还挺喜欢他的 我还从没见过一个比他更专业的扒手了
You used to like him. Never met me a better thief.
- 为什么突然之间 我们就要杀了他?  - 罗密欧啊罗密欧
- Why all of a sudden, we gotta kill him?  - Romeo, Romeo.
你有没有花一些时间...
Do you spend time...
去思考这个世界?
wondering about the world?
事物之间如何运作
The workings of things.
- 没有 先生  - 嗯 好...
- No, sir.  - Right. Well...
那最好也别现在开始思考
better not to start now.
你觉得 我偷金银和宝石是为了变得富有?
Do you think I, uh, steal gold and gems for wealth?
不
No.
让这些金银和宝石变得珍贵的原因...
What makes these most precious...
是因为他们接受光的方式不同
it's the way they accept the light.
彼得・雷克是个聪明人
Pete Lake is human.
但是那匹马...
But that horse...
那匹马可能会拖他的后腿
That horse might leave a trail.
游戏开始!
And Yahtzee!
中央车站 让我们去做了他
Grand Central Station. Let's go and kill him.
顺便试试看能不能抓住那匹马
And while we're at it, let's try and grab that horse.
你刚说那是只狗
You just said it was a dog.
去把你那帮手下叫上
Go and get the boys.
嗨
Hi.
嘿...
Hey...
家里的人都在收拾东西 准备明天去湖边度假
Everybody's all packed to go up to the lake tomorrow.
亲爱的 我后天就过去
I'll come up the next day, sweetheart.
我得等爸爸准备好我的帐篷
Daddy just has to get my tent ready.
那样你就能保持凉爽?
So you can stay cold?
对 那样我就能保持凉爽
So I can stay cold.
贝芙 你不能死
You can't die, Bev.
亲爱的...
Sweet girl...
这并不由我决定啊
it's not up to me.
再跟我讲一次吧
Tell me again.
有一场很棒的舞会...
There's this great dance...
我们都有自己的角色
and we all have our part.
而当我们的任务已尽...
And when we're done here...
可能是一生结束 也可能是分秒以后...
if it's after one life, or a thousand...
我们升入天空 成为空中的繁星
we rise up into the sky and we become stars.
再告诉我一遍他们的名字吧
Tell me their names again.
北河二星...
Castor...
北河三星...
Pollux...
五车二星...
Capella...
亲爱的 这事儿就得月黑风高的时候干
It's a great night's work, my friend.
我们往南走 直接去佛罗里达
We head south to Florida.
或者马里兰 也不是不可以
Or Maryland, maybe.
那儿听起来更像是你喜欢的地方
That sounds like the kind of place you might like.
成了 走吧
All right, let's go.
马兄
Horse.
嘿哥们儿
给点力啊
Come on.
马兄 这天马上就亮了 咱们得快点出城
Horse, it's gonna be light soon. We need to get out of town.
帕里有一帮人在找咱们
Pearly's got a hundred eyes looking after us.
快点儿
Come on.
快点儿啊
嘿...
Her...
你现在越来越贪心了
You're just getting greedy now.
好吧
Fine.
但是 下不为例啊
But this is our last score.
真不知道咱俩谁更蠢:
Don't know who's a bigger fool:
是你这个不听主人话的马 还是我这个听马话的主人
A horse who won't listen to his master, or a master who listens to his horse.
上帝啊 让我的温度降下来吧
God, make me cold.
嗨 美人儿
Hello, you beauty.
詹姆士...
James...
小詹姆士 巴塞洛缪...
James the Lesser, Bartholomew...
在响
Squeaks.
什么?
What?
地板吱呀响
It squeaks.
年久失修
Age.
你有枪
You have a gun.
对
Right.
你在这儿干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我是来打劫的
I was just robbing the place, you know.
或者说我本来是来打劫的
Or that was the idea, anyway.
你现在还想打劫吗?
Is that still your intention?
唔...
Uh...
不
No.
不 不想了
No, it isn't.
好吧 那么...
Well, then...
我觉得好像先给你倒杯茶比较礼貌
I suppose the polite thing to do would be to offer you a cup of tea.
哇哦
Wow.
你确实听懂了我说...
You did understand the part about me...
我来这儿是为了偷东西的 对吧?
coming here to steal from you, yeah?
严格意义上来讲 偷的是我爸爸的东西
It's my father, technically.
我闯进来的
I broke in.
哪儿?
Where?
他花了很大力气去防止别人进来
He takes epic measures to bar entry.
唔 事实上 你忘了关屋顶那个小房间的门 所以我就...
Well, actually, you left the door to the roof wedged open. So I just...
- 我没关?  - 对啊
- Did I?  - Yeah.
我下次可不能这样了
I must stop doing that.
对啊
Yeah.
我的意思是 你一定吓坏了
I mean, you should be scared.
唔 并没有
Well, I'm not.
不 我能看见的
No, I can see that.
这茶真不错
The tea is lovely.
这是武夷山正山小种茶
It's called Lapsang Souchong.
是从中国进口来的红茶
It's black and from China.
对我来讲 这茶有点太热了...
It's too hot for me to drink...
但是这味道总能让我回忆起伦敦
but the smell always reminds me of London.
我没去过伦敦
I've never been to London.
我不这么认为 不
I didn't think so. No. Heh.
我在那儿出生
I was born there.
如果你不介意的话 我能问下你到底怎么了吗?
What's wrong with you, if you don't mind me asking?
肺痨
Consumption.
我今年都21了 但是从来没有跟别人接吻过
I'm 21 and I've never been kissed on the mouth.
对不起 跑题了
Sorry, that came out wrong.
我不认识别人 你也看到了
I don't know anyone, you see.
我不能出去 也不能去跳舞
I can't go out. I can't dance.
我住在屋顶的帐篷里 让我的身体不至于太烫
I sleep in a tent on the roof to keep my body temperature within reason.
我可能还有...
I have maybe...
按照那个来自巴尔的摩的医生的说法 我大概还能活一年半
according to one doctor who came up from Baltimore, a year and a half.
在波士顿的时候 他们说我只剩六个月好活
In Boston, they said six months.
但是那是八个月以前了...
But that was eight months ago...
所以事实上 我应该已经死了两个月才对
so really, I'm already two months dead.
我是彼得・雷克
I'm Peter Lake.
你从哪里来呢 彼得・雷克?
And where are you from, Peter Lake?
一艘船上
A boat.
- 一艘船?  - 对啊
- A boat?  - Yeah.
我从来不知道我父母是谁 我躺在一艘船里 被吹到了布鲁克林的海岸上
I never knew my parents. Boat washed up ashore in Brooklyn.
至少别人是这么告诉我的
So I was told.
你以偷窃为生
And you steal things.
我确实偷东西 时不时偷一次
I do steal things. Yeah, from time to time.
我本来没打算干这行的
It wasn't always that way, though.
我原来一直想做一名机械师 你知道的 我总是随身带工具...
I always wanted to be a mechanic. You know, I always had a knack...
来做一些维修的工作 或者把东西拆开看看内部构造
for fixing things, getting to the insides of things.
比如保险箱
Like safes.
唔 反正最后就成这样了
Well, that's how it ended up, anyways.
后来 我和原来的老板起了点争执
Lately, I've been having a bit of a disagreement with an old boss.
我感觉你们这种行业的争执都很难解决
I should imagine disputes in your line of work are hard to settle.
是啊 确实不容易
Challenging, yeah.
你偷过最好的东西是什么?
What's the best thing you've ever stolen?
我开始怀疑我还没把最好的东西偷到手
I'm beginning to think I haven't stolen it yet.
没人比你更迷人了
Aren't you the charmer.
真好
It's been lovely.
遇到你真好 彼得・雷克
Lovely to meet you, Peter Lake.
听着 我必须马上离开纽约
Listen, I have to leave New York.
最多几个月
A few months at most.
避避风头
Let that disagreement blow over.
但是可能当我回来的时候 或许...
But maybe when I get back, I was wondering if...
我要独自去乡下了
I'm going to the country myself.
而等你回来的时候...
And by the time you get back...
我应该已经死了
I'll already be dead.
你走的时候 别偷我家的东西
Please don't steal anything on your way out.
马兄
Horse.
你把我弄进去是为了偷什么呢 马兄?
What have you gotten me into, horse?
桌子! 就那张
Table! That one.
索姆斯先生 先生 你想要多少?
Mr. Soames, sir. How many are you going to have?
一直上
Just keep them coming.
我会告诉你他们有什么企图
I'll tell you what they're trying to do.
他们想要天空充满星星
What they're trying to do is to fill the whole sky with stars.
每个善良的灵魂都上天变成一个小的点
They got little spots all picked out up there for each and every virtuous soul.
天上没有像我们这样的人的位子了 兄弟们 哈
Ain't no room in the heavens for the likes of us, though, boys. Heh.
没有帕里・索姆斯的位子 完全没有
No room for Pearly Soames. No room at all.
我很好奇他们是怎么选的翅膀的颜色
I wonder how they choose the color of their wings.
我一直想要对翅膀
I've always wanted wings.
我想要一对我自己的翅膀 你知道吗?
I'd like a pair of wings myself, you know?
请问您还需要什么吗 先生?
Anything more, sir?
是的
Oh, yes, please.
我想要南非的斑雕^...
I would like to have a South African spotted eagle owl...
如果可以 请你把它平摊开...
uh, if you could butterfly it, thank you...
然后油煎 最好再放些土豆
and pan-fry it, uh, with some potatoes would be lovely.
上面放一点欧芹 请去掉鸟嘴和鸟爪
A little bit of parsley on top. Take off the beak and the feet, please.
对不起先生 我们没有斑雕^
I'm sorry, sir. Don't got no owl.
找到她
Find her.
找到她 就能找到他
You find her, and you're gonna find him.
- 找谁?  - 那个女孩
- Find who?  - The girl.
- 什么女孩?  - 那个红头发女孩
- What girl?  - The red-haired girl.
哪个红头发女孩?
Which red-haired girl?
那个 你看到了吗 罗密欧? 那个红头发女孩
That one. You see, Romeo? That red-haired girl.
那就是他命中注定的那个人
The one who is his destiny.
就这些吗 小姐?
That all of it, miss?
就这些? 哈
All of it? Heh.
不 还早着呢
No, not even close.
怎么了?
What?
我只是想到我把你从那条小破船抱出来的那天
I just remembered the day we pulled you out of the drink in that silly little boat.
我需要一些好建议 我遇见了一个女孩
I need some friendly advice. I met a girl.
- 明白了  - 我们没有任何相似的地方
- Oh, I see.  - We've nothing in common.
嗯
Hmm.
- 她要死了  - 我们不都是吗?
- She's dying.  - Well, aren't we all?
不那么简单 她有肺病
Well, not just dying. She's consumptive.
- 啊  - 就快死了
- Ah.  - Near death.
我们才刚认识
We've only just met.
- 我觉得我已经认识她一千年了  - 嗯
- I feel like I've known her a thousand years.  - Hmm.
帕里在抓我 如果我不离开镇上 我就是在自杀
Pearly's on top of me. If I don't get out of town, I'm as good as killing myself.
彼得 有什么问题吗?
Peter, is there a question here?
我该怎么做?
What should I do?
当我想到她...
When I think of her...
我以前从来没有这样的感觉
I've never felt this way before.
为什么现在会这样?
Why now?
彼得 我们相信每个人都有10首歌
Peter, our people have 10 songs.
这些歌告诉我们每个人的内心都有一个奇迹
The songs tell us that inside of each of us is a miracle.
这个奇迹只为了等待一个人 只有那一个人
And that miracle is meant for one person, and one person alone.
当我们快要找到这个人的时候 整个宇宙都会伸出援助之手...
And when we're close, the universe reaches down...
帮助我们实现我们的命运
and helps us fulfill our destiny.
整个宇宙都会帮助我们? 到底怎么帮?
And the universe helps us? How, exactly?
宇宙在精神上指引我们
Well, the universe sends us spirit guides.
有时通过小孩子跟我们说话
Sometimes they speak to us through small children.
他们经常以动物的形式出现
They often appear as animals.
山瑟就是其中之一 他是东方之狗
One is Athansor. He's the Dog of the East.
他有时也变作一匹白马
He sometimes appears as a white horse.
也许这个女孩就是你命中注定的那个人
Perhaps this girl is the person that your miracle is for.
但是如果真是如此 你要知道:
But if so, know this:
- 福祸两相依  - 你在说什么?
- Chaos has agents too.  - What are you talking about?
上帝和恶魔?
God and the devil?
天使和魔鬼?
Angels and demons?
这是一些新的名字 是的
Those are some of the newer names, yes.
我只知道...
All I know...
我需要她...
is that I'm pulled to her...
就像我在水下需要空气一样
like air when I'm under the water.
那么 你在这里和我说话是为了什么?
So, what are you standing here talking to me for?
司机?
Driver?
我恐怕他不愿意干了
I'm afraid he's become indisposed.
我猜他突然发了一笔小财
Suddenly come into a small fortune by his standards, I imagine.
我是帕里・索姆斯
Pearly Soames.
你是?
And you might be?
我是贝芙丽・潘
Beverly Penn.
贝芙丽・潘
看来...
Well...
彼得总是癞蛤蟆想吃天鹅肉啊?
Peter does like to reach above his station, doesn't he?
而且你发烧了 是吗 亲?
And you've got a touch of the fever, haven't you, button?
时日不多了
Already only half here.
很有趣
Interesting.
你知道彼得?
You know Peter?
彼得・雷克吗?
Peter Lake?
知道他? 哦 是的
Know him? Oh, yes.
可以说 我们非常密切
We're associates, you might say.
好吧...
Well...
总之曾经是
past tense, anyway.
这个孩子很有潜力
The boy had such potential.
他很能偷
Could he steal.
偷得像艺术 像物理现象
Like art, like physics.
他把他当做自己的孩子养大
I raised him as my own.
我让他继承我的王国
I had him pegged to inherit the keys to the kingdom.
但是小彼得...
But little Peter...
他有自己的想法了
he started to having ideas.
比如不杀人就想偷得一枚钻石胸针
There's how to steal a diamond brooch without spilling blood.
不断掉指头就想偷得一枚戒指
Here's how to take a ring and leave the finger.
但是你知道 贝芙丽・潘...
But, you see, Beverly Penn...
在我的规则里...
in my line...
这些小波折才是工作的意义
it's the ripples that give the work meaning.
思想...
Ideas...
虽然利大于弊
they can do more good than harm.
但这些都是违背计划的
And that would be the opposite of the plan, you see.
非常严重的伤害
It's doing harm that is the very point.
我可能明天才去北部
I might not go upstate until tomorrow.
- 嗯  - 不用麻烦了
- Hmm.  - No bother at all.
- 我愿意付你钱  - 美女
- I'd be very happy to pay you.  - Beautiful.
生病
Sick.
- 年纪轻轻就要死了  - 我不怕你
- Too young to die.  - I'm not afraid of you.
我敢打赌你绝对是他命中注定的那个人
I'll bet that you're who his miracle is for.
如果遇到绑架我爸爸有非常严格的政策
My father has a strict policy when it comes to kidnappers.
他会救你 如果他救不了你...
He has to save you. If you can't be saved by him...
就没有然后了
job's done.
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
我喜欢看到血溅到雪地里 贝芙丽・潘
I love blood on the snow, Beverly Penn.
尤其是处女的血
Especially virginal blood.
纯洁
Unspoiled.
而又无暇
Unmolested.
贝芙丽!
Beverly!
不要!
No!
- 抓紧  - 彼得・雷克
- Hold on.  - Peter Lake.
- 快点!  - 是的 当然
- Go fast!  - Yes, clearly.
我们总会被追上的
We can't outrun them forever.
我知道! 我们得出城
I know! We have to get above the city.
沿着河往北走
Go north along the river.
- 彼得! 那里太深了!  - 抓紧!
- Peter! That's way too far down!  - Hold on!
- 抓紧?  - 抓紧!
- Hold on?  - Hold on!
彼得 彼得 等一下!
Peter. Peter, wait!
这怎么可能?
How is that even possible?
我不知道 这匹马
I don't know. This horse.
我们不能继续追他们了
We can't follow them up there.
- 为什么不能?  - 这是规矩
- Why not?  - The rules.
几百年前一个小争论的结果 真没有远见
A little dispute a couple hundred years ago. Shortsighted.
我们差一点就抓到他了
Well, we almost had him.
差一点可不够好 罗密欧
Almost is not good enough, Romeo.
你想做这个工作吗 小丁?
Do you want the job or not, Dingy?
我要见法官
I need to see the Judge.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
以你的情况...
All the excitement...
这些惊吓
and your condition.
我很好
I'm perfect.
那就好
Good.
往上游走
Head upriver.
贝芙丽!
Beverly!
谢谢
Thank you.
- 可以吗?  - 可以
- Okay?  - Yeah.
你好 小不点
Hello, little one.
哈
Mm.
我只对城市比较了解
I've only known the city.
这里叫樱湖
It's called the Lake of the Coheeries.
从小我就经常到这里来
I've been coming here since I was a little girl.
我爸爸说一切不该发生的事情这里都不会有
My father says nothing happens here that isn't supposed to.
你好
Hello.
你好 我是维拉
Hi. I'm Willa.
维拉 你好吗 维拉?
Willa. How are you, Willa?
你是贝芙丽的男朋友吗?
Are you Beverly's boyfriend?
我们进去吧
Let's go inside.
我肯定爸爸有些话要说
I'm sure father will have something to say about the matter.
你吃饭时喝酒吗?
Do you take wine with your meals?
有的时候
Sometimes.
很好
That's good.
我们今天晚上会喝酒
We'll have wine tonight.
好的
Okay.
- 红葡萄酒可以吗?  - 都行
- Would claret be all right with you?  - Anything.
但是红酒不是应该念...
But, uh, don't you pronounce it...
"克拉雷"吗?
"claret"?
不是 是克拉雷特
No. Claret.
发出t音 就像发菲利特这个音一样
You pronounce the T. Just as in fillet.
菲利特吗?
Fillet?
我一直以为是念"菲利"
I always thought it was "fillet."
不 是念菲利特
No, it's fillet.
就像沃利特 你不读"沃利"吧? 你会念成沃利特
Just as in wallet. You don't say "wallet," do you? You say wallet.
我明白了
I see.
- 你知道吗?  - 什么?
- You know what?  - Sir?
你看上去像一个混蛋
You look like a crook.
你是谁? 你是做什么的?
Who are you? What do you do?
你和贝芙丽是什么关系? 你知道她的特殊情况吗?
What is your relationship to Beverly? Are you aware of her special condition?
你的动机是什么 想要干什么 想要什么?
What are your motivations, intentions and desires?
说出事实吧 别想隐瞒
Tell the absolute truth. Don't elaborate.
如果有邻居 孩子或者仆人进来就停下 长话短说
Stop if a neighbor, child or servant comes in. And be brief.
长话短说? 这是个复杂的问题
Be brief? These are complicated questions.
如果你是我的记者 你现在就可以回去了
If you were one of my journalists, you'd be finished by now.
上帝只用了六天创造世界 学学他
God created the world in six days. Ape him.
- 好吧 我试试  - 没有必要
- Heh. I'll try.  - It's unnecessary.
- 好吧  - 没有必要
- All right.  - Unnecessary.
我叫彼得・雷克
My name is Peter Lake.
你说的没错 我是个贼 而且专业技能一流
You're right, I'm a thief, and I'm a damn good one.
我爱贝芙丽
I love Beverly.
我们之间的关系不因为名利
Our relationship goes by no name.
我没有目的
I have no intentions.
我想要她 因为我爱她
I desire her, and I am moved by love.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
我怎么能知道你不是为了虚荣心或者好奇心?
How do I know that you're not moved by vanity or curiosity?
我怎么知道你不是为了想要这个家里的钱?
How do I know you're not here for the money in this family?
我是个孤儿 孤儿没有虚荣心
I was an orphan. Orphans don't have vanity.
我不知道为什么 但是有父母的人才有资格虚荣
I'm not sure why, but one needs parents to be vain.
那钱呢?
And the money?
首先我不会从你那拿一个子
I wouldn't take a penny from you, for a start.
我不会接受帮助 甚至是一句为我说的好话
I would accept no favors, not even a kind word said on my behalf.
那她的状况呢?
And of her condition?
我以前从来没有这么爱过一个人
I've never loved much before.
死亡...
So death...
是无法避免的
hasn't been something to be avoided.
但是现在想到要失去她...
But now when I think of losing her...
有没有可能非常爱一个人他就不会死?
Is it possible to love someone so completely they simply can't die?
没有
No.
但是我是一个贼...
But I'm a thief...
就像你看到的
as you so keenly observed.
我不能偷一个生命吗?
Can't I steal just one life?
我们走着瞧吧
Well, we'll see about you.
这是不是意味着说我现在可以喝一点红葡萄酒了?
Does that mean I might try some of that claret now?
我们都喝点吧
Let's both, shall we?
还有一件事:
One more thing:
她睡在屋顶的帐篷里
She sleeps in her tent on the roof.
你不行
And you do not.
一些当地人挖蛤蚌的时候发现了我
Some locals found me while they were digging up clams.
我在一些孤儿院之间辗转了几年
I spent a few years on the bounce from orphanage to orphanage.
我猜这让我更适应流浪生活
Just got on better on the streets, I suppose.
你做什么?
What did you do?
我的意思是做什么工作
To live, I mean.
在街头唱歌跳舞挣零花钱
I danced and sang in the streets for coins.
当扒手 我和两个姑娘一起住了一段时间
Picked pockets. I lived with two girls for a while.
- 两个?  - 两个
- Two?  - Two.
你这个花花公子
Aren't you the playboy.
不是那样的
Ah, it wasn't like that.
差不多
Mostly.
我那时很小 然后帕里发现了我
I was young. And then Pearly scooped me up.
他说我有天赋
He said I had talent.
我猜不是因为你的唱歌能力
I take it wasn't for your singing.
这不管用吧? 你的体温并没有下降
It's not working, is it? You're not getting any cooler.
没有
No.
来 让我试试
Here, let me try something.
来这里
Come here.
实际上 这不管用
Actually, this isn't helping.
你能听到你的心跳吗?
Can you hear your heart?
当我发烧的时候 这差不多是我唯一能听到的
When the fever comes, it's about the only thing I can hear.
开第一个保险柜的时候 心跳的太大声 根本听不到齿轮的声音
When you crack your first safe, your heart beats so loud you can't hear the tumblers.
你必须学会平静下来 放慢心跳 才能工作
You have to learn to quieten it, slow it down, so you can work between the beats.
窍门就是列举词汇
The trick to it is lists.
说一些没有意义的词...
Meaningless words...
同时放慢呼吸
you say, as you exhale to slow down the breath.
慢慢吸气...
Inhale quietly...
呼气 不停地说直到这口气结束
exhale and say the words until the breath is gone.
- 明白了吗?  - 明白了
- Got it?  - I think so.
你想要词汇表嘛? 动物是个不错的选择 颜色 人名
Do you need a list? Animals are good. Colors. Saints.
北河二星
Castor.
北河三星
Pollux.
五车二星
Capella.
大熊星座
Ursa Major.
小熊星座
Ursa Minor.
北极星
Polaris.
彼得
Peter
这个方法管用
It's working.
继续
Go on.
昴星团
Pleiades.
昴宿星
Perseus.
仙后座
Cassiopeia.
你好
Hello.
那些是我的
Those are mine.
这些纸也是
The paper too.
我猜到了
Yeah, I figured as much.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
我喜欢在月光下画画
I like to draw by the moon.
你看 我画的不是很好 在昏暗的光线下就看不出来了
See, I'm not very good and the light helps hide it.
这是贝芙丽吗?
Is it Beverly?
我不认识别的红头发的人了
I don't know anyone else with red hair.
你爱她吗?
Do you love her?
全心全意
With all my heart.
你发誓吗?
Do you swear?
我发誓
I swear.
好吧
Okay.
跟我来
Come with me.
这是个公主床
It's a princess bed.
我让邻居的男孩为她造的
I made the neighbor boys make it for her.
他们听我的
They listen to me.
爸爸给我讲过一个故事 有一个公主死了...
Daddy told me a story about a princess who died...
但一个吻又让她活过来了
and a kiss that made her not dead anymore.
如果你在这里吻她...
If you kiss her here...
她就不会死了
she won't die.
我知道的
I know it.
好吗?
Okay?
快答应
Say okay.
好
Okay.
好的
你现在可以把我抱到床上了
You can put me to bed now.
我是帕里・索姆斯
Pearly Soames.
我有预约
I have an appointment.
你好 帕里
Hello, Pearly.
你好 很荣幸来到这 大人
Ah. Hello, Your Honor. Sir.
当然了
Oh, of course.
那个...
Eh...
我来是希望能得到豁免边界限令的特权
I'm here to request special dispensation regarding the boundaries of jurisdiction.
继续说
Proceed.
我想获准进入城北地区 大人
I'd like permission to travel north of the city, Your Honor.
噢 这可有点为难我了 帕里 根据你上次的表现
Wow, that is quite a request, Pearly, considering what happened last time.
噢 那只是个误会
Well, you know, it was a misunderstanding.
是嘛
Yeah.
好吧 小鬼 干脆一次把这事说清楚
Well, demon, let's get this over with.
帕里・索姆斯 作为曼哈顿和第五区的恶魔执行者
Pearly Soames, Warden of Manhattan and the Five Boroughs
你凭什么要我批准你的请求?
on what grounds do you make this request?
因为我发现有个人类可能会使用奇迹
I've come to believe that a human is on the verge of using his miracle
而这会对我们来说可不是个好消息
which would be a formidable advancement for the other side.
- 有证据吗?  - 守护天使现身了 大人
- Evidence?  - The presence of guardian angels, Your Honor.
东方之狗还有塞西尔・麦卓
Both the White Dog of the East and Cecil Mature.
- 还有别的吗?  - 嗯 我预见到未来的一些片段
- What else?  - Well, I've had a vision.
一个红发女孩 我用少女的血液把她画下来了
A red-haired girl I've drawn in a fugue with the blood of a virgin.
帕里 不一定就是她
Pearly, that could be anyone.
路大人 我亲眼见到他和一个这样的女人在一起
Okay, Lu, I mean, he's already been seen with a girl matching that exact description.
这个女人快死了
She's dying.
他爱她吗?
And he loves her?
百分之百 全心全意
Purely, entirely, and with all his heart.
那你的意思是他会用自己的奇迹去救她
So you believe it is his miracle to save her.
对 噢不 是的 大人
I do, sir. Yes, Your Honor. I do.
但一个人的命运往往不如眼见到的那般
A man's destiny is often not what it seems.
我明白的 我知道
I understand that, sir, I do. I do. I understand that.
但... 我... 我...
But I... Heh. I, uh...
我觉得这次准没错的
I have a feeling about this one, you know?
他是你训练出来的
You trained him.
你从街上捡到他
Picked him up off the street.
你将他视若亲生
The son you never had.
走到今天这步 惭愧吗?
Embarrassing, no?
人有失足
Shit happens.
大人
Your Honor
请批准我进入北地
I just need the permission to go north.
驳回
Denied.
这只是你的私心
This one is too personal.
你仍然不许进入北地
Your prohibition from the northern territories is upheld.
路西法大人!
Lucifer!
我一定要阻止他 现在就要!
I need to stop this one, now!
现在?
Now?
你懂什么叫"现在"
You have no idea what "now" is.
听清楚 过去天下任我畅飞
Now, I was flying.
火焰皆为我食
Now, I breathed fire and I ate them as they fled.
举手间地动山摇
Now, I whipped my tail and the winds trembled.
可现在 我确只能带着此等残破身躯
Now, I am hidden in this pale shade of flesh and bone.
眼睁睁看着不断有人得到救赎
Now, I am witness to man's eternal salvation.
再目睹他完结一生
Now, I am witness to his demise.
少跟我说道时间 小鬼
Do not speak to me of time, demon.
它最简单的变化都不是你浅薄的智力所能理解的
Its simplest ebbs and turns elude your meager understanding.
现在! 给我自寻他路!
Find another way! Now!
我带你去跳舞吧
Let me take you dancing.
迎新夜怎么样?
How about New Year's Eve?
你行吗? 你会跳舞?
Can you? Dance, I mean.
会啊 一点点
I have done. A bit.
不太多
Some.
我倒是全会
Well, I know them all.
但也仅限书本理论
From books, anyway.
听起来不错
It seems wonderful.
那就说好了
So it's sorted, then.
不行的 彼得
I can't, Peter.
是我的原因吗? 因为我没有车驾和礼服?
Is it me? Because I'm not a gentleman with a driver and the right clothes?
当然不是了
You know it's not that.
那是为什么?
What, then?
嗯 我爸爸说过 跳舞会害我丧命
Well, my father says that dancing will kill me.
这样
Ah.
爸爸总是爱过度保护
Fathers are overprotective.
别脱外套
Coat stays on.
我们一起去隔壁喝下午茶
We're all to go next door for an afternoon peppermint.
怎么一回事? 出什么问题了?
What is it? What's wrong?
已经一个下午了
It's been happening all afternoon.
是暖炉出了点问题
Has something to do with the furnace.
你爸和技师已经在下面呆了一个小时了
Your father's been down there for an hour with the mechanic.
他把所有人都送到盖米利斯家了
He sent the rest of the staff to the Gamelys'
他要你也立刻过去
and asked that you join them right away.
好啦 维拉 走吧
Now, Willa, please.
去隔壁吧 贝芙 我呢 去楼下看看能不能帮上忙
Go on next door, Bev. I'll, uh, see if I can help them out downstairs.
小姐 小小姐
Miss. The little one.
小姐
Miss.
她堵住了
She's jammed up.
让我来看看
Let me take a look.
这里危险 你该去隔壁的
We're in the red already. You should go next door.
那你们呢? 听起来动静会很大
What about you? This sounds like it's about to blow sky-high.
船要沉的话 只好一起沉了
Go down with the ship, as it were.
可这是房子 不是船
Yeah, it's a house, not a ship.
这地方是我太太弄起来的
My wife made this place.
每一件家具都是她挑选的
She picked every stitch of furniture.
不管是枕头 烛台还是窗栏
Every pillow, every sconce and window frame.
我不能丢下不管
Wouldn't do to leave it.
听着 你们现在得赶快走
Listen, you should go now.
温斯顿 走吧 快
Winston, go, go.
你也是
Now, you.
不能让蒸汽爆炸
The steam can't come.
- 你疯了  - 一下就好
- Are you mad?  - Wait.
我对复杂的系统很有一手
I have a sympathy for complex systems.
各部分零件之间的搭配运作
How things go together and come apart.
比如说锁
Like locks.
只要能弄清楚连接点
Just need to feel for the connection.
那根管子很烫 小心 避开它
That pipe's too hot, avoid it, avoid it.
这个被堵着了 说明问题出在前一个
This one's blocked. Means the problem's before it.
卡着了
It's stuck.
- 糟  - 糟了?
- Uh-oh.  - Uh-oh?
- 不小心  - 不小心?
- Qops.  - Oops?
我轻吗?
Am I light or heavy?
轻得像根羽毛
Light as a feather.
晚安 彼得・雷克
Good night, Peter Lake.
晚安 小维拉
Good night, little Willa.
我爸爸说是你救了大家
My father says you saved all our lives.
他夸张了 我只是救了他和那个技师
He's overstating things. It was just him and the furnace man's.
还有你自己的
And yours.
是的 还有我自己的命
Yeah, mine too, I suppose.
周四是迎新夜
Thursday is New Year's Eve.
我想去跳舞
I'd like to go dancing.
你真有勇气 敢来找我
You take great risk coming to me for this.
这是你欠我的 天使
You owe me, angel.
我只不过是过来讨债罢了
And this is me calling in my marker.
你要知道 我不能直接插手
You know I cannot directly intervene.
放轻松 小天使
Relax, flyboy.
这只不过是让心跳稍稍快一点
It just makes the heart beat a little faster.
一般人只有在非常激动的情况下才会出问题
Someone would have to be real excited to experience any deleterious effects.
你应该懂的
You know the rules.
欠债还钱
Debts must be paid.
那我这就算还债了
And then ours is settled.
当然 一笔勾销
Then we're square. Yes, indeed.
之后你还是善良的天使
You're a good man yourself. Well done.
我一直在想
I've been wondering.
人人都想上天
With all these trying to go up
独独你却下界
and you come down.
成为了人类 值得吗?
Was it worth it, becoming human?
还是说 你只是一时冲动?
Or was it an impulse buy?
你肯定很想念自己的翅膀吧?
You must miss the wings, right?
肯定是的吧 别急着走嘛
Oh, come on. You must.
你穿这套很帅
You look good in that suit.
那你...
You...
就是惊人的美丽了
are impossibly beautiful.
彼此彼此
So are you.
停
Stop it.
否则我会热到把脚下的雪都融化的
Or I'll melt all the snow I'm standing on.
只要你愿意 我可以让你融化全世界的雪
Give me a chance and you'll melt all the snow in the world.
好啦 走吧
Come on.
我妈妈常说 舞会场地总是比外面看起来的要大好多
My mother always said that it was bigger on the inside than it was on the outside.
- 跳一曲?  - 好的
- Shall we?  - Yes.
你太晚了
You're late.
对不起
I'm sorry.
除了你 不会再有人爱我了
If you don't make love to me now, no one ever will.
好吧 我也正打算这么做
Well, that's exactly what I'll do, then.
地点
Places.
什么地点 亲爱的?
What, Love?
我们去过的地方
Places we've been.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
贝芙丽 说话?
Beverly?
亲爱的?
回答我?
Beverly?
说话啊
Beverly.
说...
Bev...
噢 不 不 不
No, no, no.
快醒来 贝芙丽
No. Beverly.
宝贝
Baby.
不该这样的
This isn't right.
不能这样
亲爱的 贝芙丽!
Beverly. Beverly. Beverly!
别离开我
Don't leave me.
别走
Please don't go.
对不起
I'm sorry.
有他的消息了 奥特发现了他
They spotted him. Otter did.
我是指彼得・雷克 他回来了
Peter Lake, I mean. He's back.
在哪?
Where?
他先在皇后区的墓地参加了一个女人的葬礼...
He was at a graveyard in Queens burying some girl...
然后就回中央车站牵马
then went back to Grand Central for his horse.
没跟丢他吧?
Do they still have him?
噢 事实上是没法跟丢
Well, that's just the thing. They can't lose him.
- 他们只是在单纯的散步  - 散步?
- They're just walking.  - Just walking?
那我们也去散散步吧
Let's go for a little walk ourselves.
和小彼得一块儿
With little Peter Lake.
没事的 马兄
It's all right, horse.
我知道他们会找来
I know they're coming for us.
打个架也不坏
A fight will do us good.
你失败了
You failed.
你没能救活她 你最爱的红发女孩
You couldn't save her. Your beloved red-haired girl.
哈哈 她可能会是某个大人物吗?
Ha, ha. Was she gonna be somebody important?
总统? 教皇?
The president? The pope?
还是登上火星第一人的曾祖母?
The great-grandmother of the first man on Mars?
亦或者简单些
Or was it something simpler?
她的爱是伟大无私的?
That she was capable of great love?
能够温暖世界 带来光亮
The kind of love that makes the world all warm and light.
给予他人希望
And gives the others hope.
还是那种折骨断翅的爱
The kind of love that tilts the scales.
不管怎么说 现在都不重要了
Well, it doesn't matter.
反正她已经死了
She's dead.
没有温度 死尸一具
Cold. Dead.
被土掩埋
And already in the ground.
你以为你能逃开?
Quit me?
那是不可能的 孩子
You don't quit me, boy.
我都记不清是何时开始...
I've been blackening souls...
抹黑灵魂 碾碎奇迹的
and crushing miracles for longer than I can remember.
你是不是也在想 为何世界如此混乱
Do you ever ask yourself why the universe goes to all this trouble
既然要你走完人生长路 却有我做其中的拦路虎?
to help you fulfill your destiny and then throws me in your path?
也许只是因为上帝也如同我们一样嗜血
Maybe it's because God is just as bloodthirsty as the rest of us.
也许是他也厌烦了无尽的善与光
Maybe he doesn't like eternal benevolence and light.
也许他也喜欢战斗
Maybe he just likes a good fight.
我不知道你在说什么 但我要告诉你:
I have no idea what you're talking about. But I'll tell you one thing:
真遗憾你爸当年没有把你弄死
It's a shame your daddy didn't do a better job on your neck with that soda bottle.
是嘛 小彼得?
Is that right, little Peter Lake?
那就让我们看看该怎么对你下手了
Well, let's see what we're gonna do with you.
快 前进!
Come on. Move! Move it!
你还行吗 伙计?
How are you, lads?
- 给我活剥那只狗的皮  - 不!
- Skin that white dog alive.  - No!
撒网!
Bring in the net!
- 拿下他!  - 你快走
- Get him!  - I want you to go.
马儿 快走!
Horse, go!
稳住
Hold, boys.
马兄!
Horse!
走啊
Go.
快走
等一下 别急
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
让我来
Well, well, well.
嗨 朋友
Hey, pal.
想找谁?
You looking for someone in particular?
呃...
L...
我也不知道
I don't know.
我记不得了
I can't remember.
什么都不记得了
I can't remember anything.
当真爱被遗失
When true love is lost
生命丧失意义
life can bleed of all meaning.
人也仅剩空壳
We are left blank.
但请记住 命运仍存转机
But the possibility of destiny remains.
虽然关于前路 迷雾重重
What we are meant for may yet be discovered.
多年以后
And once in a very long while
重拾的道路将会打败一切时间
that journey to find our destiny may defeat even time itself.
2014年 纽约
你是谁?
Who are you?
彼得 转机来了
Pete, here's your change.
我撞到了你
I smashed into you.
没错 没事吧?
You did. Are you all right?
我重还是轻?
Am I light or heavy?
轻得像羽毛
Light as a feather.
我叫艾比 你呢?
I'm Abby. What's your name?
我不知道
I don't know.
人人都知道自己的名字
Everybody knows their name.
不包括我
Not me.
你真笨
You're silly.
看 那有一颗星
Look. There's a star.
就连星星也有名字
Even the stars have names.
- 什么?  - 星星们
- What?  - The stars.
我只是记不得他们叫什么
I just can't remember them.
北河二星
Castor.
好了 艾比
Abby.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
对不起
Sorry.
彼得・雷克?
那个混蛋
That son of a bitch.
他不可能还活着的
He can't still be alive.
- 罗密欧 找到这个男人  - 我是凯撒
- Romeo, find this man.  - Cesar.
罗密欧是我爷爷
Romeo was my grandfather.
好吧 凯撒...
Cesar...
别的事先放下
drop everything else.
给我找到这个男人
Find this man.
老板 这人应该有上百岁了吧
Boss, this is like a hundred years old.
我看起来像是不知道这一点吗?
Do I, uh, strike you as a man who wouldn't know that?
不 先生 我没有...
No, sir. I didn't...
很抱歉 我不...
I'm sorry, sir. I didn't...
还记得我是怎么干掉你爷爷的吗?
Remember I told you how I killed your grandfather?
我错了 老板
Sorry, sir.
找到这个男人
Find that man.
找到他
Find him.
我们当初可能是找错红头发的人了
We may have killed the wrong redhead.
麻烦你 我想找艾萨克・潘
Isaac Penn, please.
前台说他在这里面
The woman out front said he was back here.
这里确实是艾萨克・潘的阅览室
This is the Isaac Penn Reading Room.
对对 如果可以的话 我想和他本人谈谈
Yeah, I mean, I'd like to speak with him if I could.
玩笑开得不错啊
Be a neat trick.
潘在90年前就死了
Penn's been dead 90 years.
呵呵 在哈德逊大街上有个叫樱的戏院
Heh. There's a theater on Hudson Street called the Theater of the Coheeries.
你能给我点关于它的相关信息吗?
Could you, uh, tell me if you have any information on it, please?
它是艾萨克・潘捐助的
Isaac Penn donated it.
不行 我这里能看到词条...
Nope. I see it here...
但相关信息没有从胶片上录入下来
but the information on it hasn't been cataloged from the microfiche.
好吧 那我能看下那个胶什么的东西吗?
Okay, might I see them, please? These micro fish.
当然 两种身份证件 填完表 再等两周审批...
Sure. Two forms of ID, fill this out, two-week approval period...
你就可以随便搜查资料了
and you can search to your heart's delight.
我能不能...? 我的意思是...
Can I just...? I mean...
对不起 我帮不了你
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
现在有太多规定
There's so many regulations these days.
- 嗨 我是维吉尼亚・嘉明丽  - 嗨 我是彼得・雷克
- Hi, I'm Virginia Gamely.  - Hi, Peter Lake.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi.  - Hi.
我在哪里认识过你吗?
Do I know you from somewhere?
不 我可不这么认为
I don't think so, no. No.
尽管我也不确定
Although I can't be sure.
我没有记忆...
I've had no memory...
- 从我记事时候起就没有  - 哦
- for as long as I can remember.  - Oh.
或许我的头被撞击过 虽然我没找到疤
Maybe there was once a blow on the head, although I can't find a scar.
整个世界看起来就像刚刚升起的浓雾
And the whole world has seemed like a deep fog that's just now beginning to lift.
尽管我喜欢升得更快点儿
Although not fast enough for my liking.
我确信...
I've become convinced...
如果我能知道樱是什么...
that if I could just learn what this Coheeries is...
或许能帮助唤起我的记忆
it may help jog my memory.
可是现在他们告诉我得等两个星期...
But now they're telling me I have to wait two weeks...
我不得不用两种身份证件 我要是有证件就不需要来这里找回记忆了
and I have to have two forms of ID that I don't have just to even get back there.
而现在我越来越怀疑 我或许能更快得到自己需要的...
But I have a growing suspicion that I may be able to get what I need faster...
就跟每个人晚上回家过夜一样快
as soon as everybody goes home for the night.
如果我知道微缩胶片是什么样就好了
If only I knew what a micro fish looked like.
你知道 像这种地方的安全系统总是很完备的
You know, places like this have all sorts of security systems.
不知怎么 我发现自己很无畏
Well, somehow I find myself undaunted.
你很幸运 我在这工作 所以我不需要任何批准
Well, you're in luck. I work here, so I don't need any approvals.
是不是啊 杰克?
Isn't that right, Jack?
嘉明丽小姐 新闻记者可以随意进出
Reporters come and go as they please, Ms. Gamely.
- 这边请  - 谢谢帮忙
- There you go.  - I appreciate the help.
反正我现在不走运
I wasn't having any luck anyway.
你在找什么?
What were you looking for?
治疗癌症的方法
A cure for cancer, I suppose.
所以...
So...
应该是在...
this should go...
这儿
here.
还有...
And...
啊
Aw.
等一下
Wait a sec.
让我看看
Let me see.
还以为你连显微胶片是什么都不知道
Thought you didn't even know what microfiche were.
我刚刚掌握了机器的诀窍
I just got a knack with machines.
试试
Try it now.
那不是个剧院
Well, that's not a theater.
可恶 估计是贴错了标签
Damn. Guess it's mislabeled.
樱不是剧院
Coheeries isn't a theater.
是一座小镇
It's a town.
哦
Oh.
那是老潘
That's old man Penn.
她弹奏勃拉姆斯的曲子
She played Brahms.
是贝芙丽
Beverly.
她的名字叫...
Her name was...
她叫贝芙丽
Her name was Beverly.
那是...
That's...
这不可能
It can't be.
是你爸爸?
Your father?
发生什么事了?
What's happening here?
她去世了
She's dead.
已经走了很久
She's long gone.
他们都死去一百年了
They're all dead a hundred years.
不是所有人
Not all of them.
- 什么事?  - 嗨 呃...
- Yes?  - Hi. Um...
我叫弗吉尼亚・嘉明丽 我在这上班
My name is Virginia Gamely. Uh, I work here.
- 恩?  - 我为美食专栏写作
- Yes?  - I write the food column.
- 恩?  - 她在吗?
- Yes?  - Is she in?
你有预约吗 我怎么不知道?
Do you have an appointment I'm not aware of?
谢谢你 大使先生 很高兴我们能达成共识
Thank you, Mr. Ambassador. I'm glad we could come to an understanding.
玛吉 我午饭想吃奶昔
I think I'll have a milkshake for lunch, Marge.
你觉得利瓦特医生会杀了我吗?
Do you think Dr. Levi would kill me?
巧克力味 要涂生奶油
Chocolate with whipped cream.
潘女士?
Ms. Penn?
维拉
Willa.
小维拉
Little Willa.
彼得・雷克
Peter Lake.
就在那儿
It's right up there.
你在哪找到他的?
Where did you find him?
我想是他找到了我
I think he found me.
这怎么可能?
How is this really possible?
人生漫长 你会看到
Well, in a life this long, you do see things.
一些我们已知世界里没有的事物
Things that don't always add up to the world we think we know.
恩
Hmm.
我一直保留着那张桌子
I've always held on to that table.
没什么特别的 我也说不上来为什么
Nothing special, can't say why.
他深爱我的姐姐
He loved my sister terribly.
她就像一束亮光
She was like a bright light.
她怎么死的?
How did she die?
肺痨
Consumption.
她死去的那一晚...
The night she died...
我为她搜寻了整个天空
I searched the sky for her.
我想 我在猎户座找到了她
And I found her there in Orion's Belt, I think.
她曾说过 当我们完成了地球上的事业...
She used to say that when we finished our work on Earth...
我们就会飞起来 变成星星
we would fly up and become stars.
什么事业?
What work?
她才21岁
She was 21.
她怎么可能已经完结了呢?
How could she have possibly been finished?
为什么我依然活着?
Why am I still alive?
彼得 看看你 这么多年一直没有改变
Well, I look at you, Peter, unchanged after all these years.
也许你仍然有要做的事情
Maybe there's something you are still meant to do.
是什么?
What?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我给你沏杯茶怎么样?
May I make you some tea?
好的 谢谢
Please.
谢谢你带我回到这里
Thank you for bringing me back here.
我感觉我们不会再见了 是吗?
I have a feeling we won't see each other again, will we?
跟长辈顶嘴不礼貌哦
It's poor manners to talk back to your elders.
严格来说 我比你年纪大
Technically, I think I'm older than you.
是的 我觉得不会再见
No, I have a feeling we won't.
再见 彼得・雷克
Goodbye, Peter Lake.
再见 小维拉
Goodbye, little Willa.
小姐 我期待你的下一份食谱
I'm looking forward to your next recipe, young lady.
我喜欢吃山核桃
I rather like pecans.
我三点半得去接女儿
I have to pick up my daughter at 3:30.
所以...
So, um...
我住在十二街
I live down on 12th Street.
我买了一只鸡...
I've got a chicken...
如果你喜欢鸡肉的话
if you like chicken.
我很乐意 但是...
I would like that, but, um...
- 我还有一些事情要做...  - 好吧
- Well, I have a few things I need to...  - Okay.
- 好的  - 嘿
- Okay.  - Hey.
- 小心点  - 谢谢
- Take care.  - Thank you.
告诉头儿我们找到他了
Tell the boss that we found him.
他怎么会还活着? 路大人 我们在说些什么?
How is he still alive? What are we talking about here, Lu?
我们在讨论一个永久的话题 天上的星星
We're talking about what we are always talking about.Stars in the sky.
奇迹
Miracles.
- 我阻止了他救她  - 帕里
- I stopped him from saving her.  - Pearly.
不是他的奇迹
Not his miracle.
是她的
Hers.
什么?
What?
你一直念念不忘去阻止他...
You were so fixated on stopping him...
你完全忽略了她
you missed her entirely.
她使得他如此爱她 以至于不会死去
She made him love her so much that he could not die.
他就是她的奇迹
He was her miracle.
我想杀了他 我希望他留在死亡里
I want to kill him, and I want him to stay dead.
我想让他变成白雪 散落在四面八方
I want him turned into snow and scattered to the four winds.
恩
Mm.
旧的秩序仍将适用 你的战斗将会是致命的
Older rules would apply. You would be fighting as a mortal.
你不觉得 这太极端了吗?
That's rather extreme, don't you think?
我来告诉你一些让你血液冰冷的事情
I'll tell you something that should chill your blood.
无论我们把局面怎样扭转...
No matter how far we tip the scales our way...
无论他们多少人被打入黑暗...
no matter how many of them we turn dark...
没有什么能消灭他们的希望
nothing seems to break their capacity for hope.
他们自由传播希望 就像学前班集市上的流感
They pass it back and forth like the flu at a preschool fair.
路西法 我们输了
We're losing, Lucifer.
一次只能有一颗明亮的星星 我们输了
One bright star at a time, we're losing.
帕里 你得说出那些话
You will have to say the words, Pearly.
好的
Right.
我 帕里・索姆斯...
I, Pearly Soames...
第五区的恶魔执行者...
Demon Enforcer of the Five Boroughs...
堕落军团的黑暗骑士...
Black Knight of the Armies of the Fallen...
路西法 您本人忠心耿耿和心甘情愿的仆人...
and faithful and willing servant to Lucifer, your good self...
在此请求 这场战斗中失败的一方...
hereby request that the loser of the fight...
在人类 彼得・雷克 还有我之间...
between the human, Peter Lake, and myself...
必有人真正死去
die the one true death.
再考虑一下
Reconsider.
不
No.
帕里 最后一次机会
Last chance, Pearly.
同意
Granted.
帕里...
Pearly...
注意星光
Watch out for the starlight.
路大人 你说什么?
What are you talking about, Lu?
小心点 我不想失去你
Be careful. I would hate to lose you.
为什么?
Why?
你习惯了人类
You get used to people.
豆芽吃了吗?
Did you try the Brussels sprouts yet?
妈妈 我不饿
I'm not really that hungry, Mom.
宝贝 就试着吃点儿 好吗?
Just try to eat something, baby, okay?
好
Okay.
给你
Here you go.
- 妈妈?  - 怎么了 孩子?
- Mama?  - Yes, baby?
你觉得 我们死去以后会去哪儿呢?
Where do you think we go when we die?
来
Come here.
是谁?
Hello?
你说住在十二街 这儿是唯一一家姓嘉明丽的
You said 12th Street, and you're the only Gamelys on 12th Street.
我的确喜欢吃鸡
And I do like chicken.
- 你坐船漂过来的?  - 别人是这么对我说的
- You floated here? In a boat?  - That's what I was told.
我们有巧克力 草莓...
We have chocolate, strawberry...
还有开心果
and pistachio.
开心果 开心果?
Pistachio. Pistachio?
- 她讨厌香草  - 我讨厌香草
- She hates vanilla.  - I hate vanilla.
妈妈
Mama.
扶她躺下来
Lay her down.
嘿 宝贝 好的
Hey, baby. All right.
放松 放松 放松 妈妈在这儿
Relax. Relax, relax. Mama's here.
没事的 没事的 宝贝 妈妈在这儿
It's all right. It's all right, darling. Mama's here.
她得了癫痫
She gets seizures.
她现在要睡觉
She'll sleep now.
艾比是红头发
Abby has red hair.
我们必须得走 现在
We have to go. Now.
不 没地方可去
No. There's nowhere to go.
画里的女孩...
The girl in the pictures...
我一直在画的女孩...
the girl I've been drawing...
自始至终是她
it was her all along.
彼得 她得了癌症
She has cancer, Peter.
医生们说她快要死了
Her doctors say she's dying.
我想我知道怎样救她
I think I know how to save her.
他们说唯有奇迹可以
They said only a miracle.
我
Me.
这是我活着的原因
That's why I stayed alive.
是为了她
For her.
我是她的奇迹
I'm her miracle.
这简直是疯了
This is crazy.
我能救她 我知道我能
I can save her. I know I can.
我们得离开
We have to go.
有一群人要来这儿伤害我 我想他们也想要伤害艾比
There are men coming who mean to harm me. I think they mean to harm Abby too.
请相信我
Trust me, please.
屋顶有匹马
There's a horse on the roof.
是的
There is.
你好 老朋友
Hello, my old friend.
好久不见
It's been a very long time.
来 把她给我
Here. Give her to me.
快来
Come on.
- 你知道该去哪儿吧 马儿  - 什么?
- You know where to go, horse.  - What?
嘘 让他自己解答
Shh. Let him do the math.
好的
Okay.
- 她怎么样了?  - 还在睡着
- How is she?  - Still sleeping.
嘿
Hey.
樱
Coheeries.
看起来被遗弃了
It looks forgotten.
来 这边走
Come on, this way.
他们怎么会 呃...? 上帝 管他们是谁
What about those, uh...? Whoever they were. Christ.
我想他们不会跟到这儿
I don't think they can follow us up here.
你认为不会 这是安慰的话
You don't think. That's reassuring.
不 我相当肯定
No, I'm fairly sure.
规则变了
Rules change.
小彼得想要救人
Little Peter wants to save someone.
可是我想战斗
But I want to fight.
彼得 很高兴见到你
Good to see you, Peter.
平心而论 帕里 我没法对你说同样的话
In fairness, I can't say the same thing about you, Pearly.
看来我把红头发的人弄混了
Well, it seems I got my redheads mixed up.
无心之过
Honest mistake.
我会改正的
I'll fix it.
我们有20个人
There's 20 of us.
你只有一个
And there's just the one of you.
今晚不会有奇迹了
There'll be no miracles tonight.
她的命运已经注定了
And her destiny is getting skewered.
马儿
Horse.
马儿 我想你知道怎么做
I suppose you know what to do, horse.
这个白狗 一直是懦夫!
Always a coward, that White Dog!
伙计们
Boys.
帕里 你为什么要这么做?
Why do you do it, Pearly?
你自己都不知道吧?
Do you even know?
我知道我的命运
I know my destiny.
是时候让你去面对命运了
And it's high time you met yours.
它向冰面俯冲了!
Off the ice!
好吧
Right, then.
艾比?
Abby?
艾比
Abby.
哦 上帝 不
Oh, Jesus. No.
一百年前 一个小姑娘做了这张床 许下愿望 她现在已成为老妇
A bed of wishes made 100 years ago by a little girl who's now an old woman.
这张床是为了拯救一个红头发的姑娘 避免她在年轻时死去
A bed made to save a girl with flaming red hair from dying too young.
这是一个能产生奇迹的地方
A place made for a miracle.
现在 我只是个机械师 可是我们如果没有机器又是什么呢?
Now, I'm just a mechanic, but what are we if not machines?
这些机器需要来自宇宙的一点帮助才能运转
Machines that need a little help from the universe to run.
艾比
Abby.
这是我们去爱的原因吗?
Is this why we love at all?
为了拯救?
To save?
你一直就是那个人 不是吗?
You were always the one, weren't you?
拜托 你肯定是那个我要去拯救的人
Please, you were always the one I was meant to save.
回来
Come back.
求求你活过来
Please come back.
不
No.
妈妈?
Mama?
为什么大家都在哭?
Why is everybody crying?
我是又生病失去知觉了吗?
Did I get sick and pass out again?
是的 艾比
Yes, Abby.
不过你现在好些了
But you're better now.
为什么这么多事物都齐心协力去救一个小姑娘呢?
Why would so many things conspire to save one little girl's life?
但是如果不仅仅是艾比需要帮助呢?
But what if it wasn't just Abby?
如果她不比我们任何人特殊呢?
What if she is no more or less special than any of us?
如果我们每个人都很特别...
What if we are all unique...
宇宙对我们同等喜爱会怎么样?
and the universe loves us all equally?
爱的如此之深 以至于它穿越许多个世纪...
So much so that it bends over backwards across the centuries...
为我们每一个人
for each and every one of us.
有时候 我们很幸运 能够看见
And sometimes, we are just lucky enough to see it.
众生平等
No life is more important than another.
没有什么事物是毫无意义的
And nothing has been without purpose.
没有
Nothing.
假使我们都是这伟大蓝图的一部分呢? 某一天我们或许会了解的伟大蓝图
What if we are all part of a great pattern that we may someday understand?
有一天 当我们完成独自一人有能力做的事情...
And one day, when we have done what we alone are capable of doing...
我们会升起 与自己最爱的人相聚...
we get to rise up and reunite with those we have loved the most...
永远拥抱在一起
forever embraced.
假使我们变成了星星会怎么样?
What if we get to become stars?
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
协调: 影子
翻译: 轩一一 优兰达子 。私 风露清愁
校对: 有个饭团